Looks like the Deep Seek team is back
again with a fresh new update with the
introduction of their Deepseek V3.1
Terminus model. This release maintains
the model's original capabilities while
addressing several user reported issues.
It has key improvements including
enhanced performance of both the code
agent as well as the search agent along
with better language consistency. But
overall, this Terminus model is
delivering more stable and reliable
output across various sorts of
benchmarks compared to its previous
version. Now, when you compare the
Terminus model to their earlier Deepseek
V3.1 update, the improvements are quite
noticeable, though it's not
groundbreaking, but it's still a decent
upgrade. The benchmarks show a slight
increase in the sway verified benchmark
test with pagentic tool use and it is
showcasing upgrades in reasoning
benchmarks such as MMLU humanities last
exam as well as a slight modest bump in
live codebench. Now overall these
performance are particularly with
reasoning mode enabled without tool use
but in essence deepseek v3.1 terminus
isn't a massive leap forward but it
offers meaningful upgrades in key areas
like coding performance reasoning search
agent capabilities and it makes it an
overall great worthwhile update for many
users like various developers.
Now what you'll notice is that there's
actually a slight decrease in
performance on certain benchmarks like
code force as well as ADR polygon. And
the reason why is because there's
trade-offs in optimization. The team
might be focusing on improving stability
with its reasoning capabilities which is
why you see these decreases could be
also benchmark variance a focus on
fine-tuning the gentic tool use
benchmarks which is why you see an
increase on these benchmarks like sway
verified as well as the terminal bench.
So overall, it's not something huge to
or like something to panic about, but it
is something that they have done as a
trade-off in terms of optimization. But
here's my two cents. If you're looking
for an open-source model that packs
performance while also being super
efficient, the Deepseek V3.1 Terminus is
the model of your choice. This is due to
its pricing where it's listed at 27
cents for 1 million input tokens and $1
per 1 million output tokens. The only
downside is is the context, which isn't
massive, but it's relative to the
different models that we've seen on this
channel, where it's listed to have 131k
context window with a 65.6K max output.
But overall, it delivers strong agentic
performance and reasoning, which is
definitely an unbeatable value, which
we're going to be showcasing throughout
today's video. If you've been hearing
all the hype about AI agents, but
wondering what actually works, that is
exactly why today I'm excited to
showcase this guide by HubSpot called
Master AI Agents in 2025. The strategic
advantage. This practical guide from
HubSpot CMO and CVP of marketing cuts
through the noise, showing you where to
start, which AI agent application
delivers real value, and how to
implement them for real business impact.
Inside, you'll discover how to automate
marketing workflows with AI content
creation and analytics, accelerate sales
with prospect research and smarter
follow-ups, and even streamline
operations with automated documentation
and realtime insights. Plus, you'll get
a step-by-step blueprint for selecting,
deploying, and measuring agents that
boost efficiency without replacing jobs.
So, unlock your competitive advantage.
Download the free master AI agents in
2025 guide with the link in the
description below. Don't watch the AI
revolution. Beat it. Download this for
free today and gain the strategies
forward thinking companies are already
using to stay ahead. Now, if you're
looking to get started with this model,
you can definitely do so through
accessing it via Deep Seek's chatbot,
which has already implemented the new
Terminus model directly. Here you also
have the ability to access it via API
that DeepC provides. And if you want to
use external provider like open router,
you can even use this as well. So let's
just get started with all the benchmark
tests. This is where we're going to
first have it create a SAS landing page
that has many features. Essentially,
this is something that I usually test
any model out to get a good feel of its
front-end capabilities as well as how
well it is in terms of taking a creative
approach with the prompt that I state to
add as many features and how well it is
in terms of just coding out various
components. So, let's see what it
actually ends up generating. Now, in the
meantime, I'm going to have Kilo Code
tackle this task powered by the DeepSeek
Terminus model where I'm going to have
it create a modern web browser that's
similar to Chrome. And I recommend that
you use Kilo Code as well cuz this is a
way for you to actually access free
credits and get some generations with a
powerful coding agent. But essentially,
this is a prompt that evaluates the
model's ability to generate creative
product ideas. And I'm trying to have it
propose a technical feature where it can
design a browser concept that balances
different functionalities as well as
innovation. So you can see right now
with its reasoning capabilities, it is
working on in-depth analysis on how it
can tackle this task. And then it's
going to deploy multiple agents to
tackle it. So while this is generating,
let's actually now take a look at what
the SAS landing page looks like. Let's
click run. And this is our SAS landing
page, which definitely looks like a
typical AI generated SAS landing page,
but it has all the components that you
would expect. And I told it to add lots
of features. And I guess it kind of did
cuz it added how it works to the
section, powerful features with
animations, different uh cards with
different components, which you can see
has been displayed. And overall, it's
well structured and it looks pretty
decent. So, it did pass this test and it
does better than the previous version,
which is definitely good to see. Now,
with the reasoning enabled, this is
where it's going to think before
actually responding. And this is where
we're going to get a better thoughtput
answer. And essentially, I'm sending in
this prompt where I'm telling it that
I'm a truck driver making around 65K a
year and I'm aiming to retire in 30
years. Could you draft up a portfolio
management proposal? Essentially, it
will focus on numerical reasoning as
well as forecasting where it's going to
be able to determine the retirement
plan. It is also going to focus on
different domains like asset collection,
risk management. And one thing I noticed
right away is that didn't actually think
too much. It is something that thought
for 9 seconds which isn't a lot for a
reasoning model but overall it worked on
creating a plan talking about the core
principles the different parts to take
to accomplish this strategic plan like
the action plan where to put your money
401k where if you're in the states you
can invest in that or a similar plan
depending on the country uh different
steps you can take maxing it out the
portfolio etc etc but it is still going
and we'll take a final look at it
afterwards. And overall, we're trying to
see how well it is in terms of tailoring
a specific plan based off the income
timeline as well as goal. Now, I sent in
this exact prompt to the open router
provider, and I got a better detailed
answer that looks a lot structured. And
this is something that I found to be
better compared to what I got from their
chatbot. I don't know why, but what I
got from this open router answer is
definitely better than the chatbot. And
it looks like it did a great job in
focusing on tailoring a plan to the
specific income that set as well as the
timeline. So after 30 years, your
contribution alone would total 180k with
compounding and the portfolio could be
worth approximately 567K
in today's dollar according to
inflation, which is pretty cool. So, it
was able to also consider inflation, the
different principles, as well as how you
can set it up depending on which country
you're in. Reasoning wise, I definitely
prefer these answers compared to its
previous version. So, that's good to
see. But now that we have finished
generating the browser, let's actually
take a look at it where we can reveal
this in the file explorer and open it
up. And there we go. This is the Nexus
browser. This is something that it had
generated and it looks pretty cool. You
have the main dashboard, I guess, where
you can access different websites.
Obviously, it's not going to work, but
you can see that I can click on things
and I can search up different websites.
I have an extension store, which is
cool. I also have a settings tab I can
refresh, but overall, it generated the
base structure of a browser. Next up,
I'm going to have it create a butterfly
in SVG code. Essentially, we're trying
to see how proficient it is in
generating SVG code, as well as if it's
able to display a symmetrical butterfly
with its generations. Now, it looks like
it is finished. We can click on run. And
that does not look like a butterfly, but
I guess it got the main body type right.
I'm going to use reasoning, and I'm
actually going to use the open router
provider to have it generate a butterfly
to see if we get a different answer. So,
I've copied the code for the SVG
butterfly, and I'm going to go over to
this online SVG viewer and paste it in.
And it looks like it failed at this,
which is kind of surprising because
usually with my last video on the
Deepseek V3.1, I was able to create a
butterfly with uh SVG code. So, it's
kind of surprising.
So, I've actually tried it again,
creating a butterfly with deep link
enabled. And this is, I guess, the best
butterfly we've gotten so far. I guess
it was trying to animate it, but it
didn't actually create the main
structure of the wings. So, I guess this
is kind of a fail, which is kind of
surprising to see. Now, lastly, I'm
going to have it create a Minecraft
clone. And usually, most models now are
able to actually generate this. And
looking at this so far, it definitely
looks pretty cool. Now, the functions
don't look great cuz I'm falling out of
the map for some reason, but it added
sound, which is actually pretty cool.
I'm able to place blocks. I can break
things. And it looks like I'm falling
out of the world. So, I guess a lot of
the functions don't actually work as
it's supposed to, but I guess it's
decent cuz I'm like struggling to stay
on the world, but I can actually place
things down, which is, I guess, kind of
functional. But overall, you can say it
kind of passed it cuz it added a lot of
different features and it created the
main structure of a 3D Minecraft clone.
If you like this video and would love to
support the channel, you can consider
donating to my channel through the super
thanks option below. Or you can consider
joining our private Discord where you
can access multiple subscriptions to
different AI tools for free on a monthly
basis, plus daily AI news and exclusive
content, plus a lot more. But that's
basically guys for today's video on the
Deep Seek V3.1 Terminus model. This is a
costefficient, high-erforming model
which I definitely recommend that you
try out and it's something that you can
easily get started with through their
chatbot. But that's basically it guys.
Let me know what you guys think in the
description or the comment section
below. I'll leave all these links in the
description below. Make sure you go
ahead and subscribe to the second
channel. Join the newsletter. Join our
private discord. Follow me on Twitter.
And lastly, make sure you guys
subscribe, turn on notification bell,
like this video, and please take a look
at our previous videos so that you can
stay upto date with the latest AI news.
But with that thought, guys, have an
amazing day. Spread positivity and I'll
see you guys fairly shortly.